Every story has a hero. Every hero has a destiny. Every saga has an end.
Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith is a adventure,
action, science fiction film directed by George Lucas.
When the sinister Sith unveil a thousand-year-old plot to rule the galaxy, the
Republic crumbles and from its ashes rises the evil Galactic Empire.
Jedi hero Anakin Skywalker must choose a side.
Anakin Skywalker / Darth Vader, played by Hayden Christensen.
Obi-Wan Kenobi, played by Ewan McGregor.
Padmé Amidala, played by Natalie Portman.
Chancellor Palpatine / Darth Sidious, played by Ian McDiarmid.
Mace Windu, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Senator Bail Organa, played by Jimmy Smits.
Star Wars: Episode III – Revenge of the Sith is an action video
game based on the 2005 film of the same name.
It was released on May 5, 2005, for the PlayStation 2, Xbox,
Game Boy Advance, Nintendo DS, and Symbian OS.
For the Xbox 360's backwards compatible lineup, Revenge of the Sith is one
out of the 400+ backwards compatible games for the 360.
As part of the PlayStation 2 classics program, the PlayStation 2 version was re-released in Europe on the
PlayStation Network on February 11, 2015, and in North America on April 28, 2015 for PlayStation 3.
Meanwhile, the Xbox version was also added to the backwards compatibility
list for the Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S on November 15, 2021.
A PlayStation Portable version was in development, but was cancelled.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of showdown, lava, fight, politics, volcano.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.